

<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>/</id>
  <title>William Freidank</title>
  <subtitle>A place to share my musings in engineering, research, and the various corners of life.</subtitle>
  <updated>2025-06-07T09:00:58-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>William Freidank</name>
    <uri>/</uri>
  </author>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="/feed.xml"/>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"
    href="/"/>
  <generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator>
  <rights> © 2025 William Freidank </rights>
  <icon>/assets/img/favicons/favicon.ico</icon>
  <logo>/assets/img/favicons/favicon-96x96.png</logo>


  
  <entry>
    <title>Self-love, Shame, and Narcissism</title>
    <link href="/posts/self_love/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Self-love, Shame, and Narcissism" />
    <published>2025-06-05T20:00:00-04:00</published>
  
    <updated>2025-06-05T20:00:00-04:00</updated>
  
    <id>/posts/self_love/</id>
    <content type="text/html" src="/posts/self_love/" />
    <author>
      <name>freidank</name>
    </author>

  
    
    <category term="Reflections" />
    
  

  <summary>Para poder amar, no para enamorarme sino para amar a través de aquel enamoramiento, tengo, y será mi deseo, darme. Pero si no estoy convencido de que tengo algo digno de dar, entonces como voy a amar? Por miedo y vergüenza, no me daré según realmente soy, y no amaré. Me daré parcialmente; me dejaré cambiar fácilmente, pretenderé ser algo diferente a lo que soy, aceptaré lo que no aceptaría, dud...</summary>

  </entry>

  
  <entry>
    <title>McBaby - Now 50% Off</title>
    <link href="/posts/mcbaby/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="McBaby - Now 50% Off" />
    <published>2025-06-03T20:00:00-04:00</published>
  
    <updated>2025-06-07T09:00:52-04:00</updated>
  
    <id>/posts/mcbaby/</id>
    <content type="text/html" src="/posts/mcbaby/" />
    <author>
      <name>freidank</name>
    </author>

  
    
    <category term="Reflections" />
    
  

  <summary>I have the great gift of working in my lab with one the most genuine and creatively funny individuals I know. His humor is wholesome and always accompanies his generosity towards us colleagues. His work ethic is sound, his aptitude inspires, and his sincerity wins trust. It’s not just a nice-to-have; any leader understands the critical weight of character and trust for sound team dynamics. This...</summary>

  </entry>

  
  <entry>
    <title>Transparent Grime, Glare, &amp; Noise Removal</title>
    <link href="/posts/transparent_grime_removal/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Transparent Grime, Glare, &amp;amp; Noise Removal" />
    <published>2025-04-29T00:00:00-04:00</published>
  
    <updated>2025-04-29T16:10:44-04:00</updated>
  
    <id>/posts/transparent_grime_removal/</id>
    <content type="text/html" src="/posts/transparent_grime_removal/" />
    <author>
      <name>freidank</name>
    </author>

  
    
    <category term="Robotics" />
    
  

  <summary>Question: Can we develop an algorithm to separate distant visual features of interest from transparent foreground noise?  Sensors and robust signal processing form one leg of the proverbial Sense-Decide-Act loop. But as robotocists are well-aware, our sensors rarely receive or provide pristine information. It’s up to us to either improve our sensing capabilities or design post-processing algori...</summary>

  </entry>

  
  <entry>
    <title>Artificial Potential Fields - The Secant Method</title>
    <link href="/posts/artificial_potential_field_secant/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Artificial Potential Fields - The Secant Method" />
    <published>2023-02-01T23:00:00-05:00</published>
  
    <updated>2025-04-29T10:09:48-04:00</updated>
  
    <id>/posts/artificial_potential_field_secant/</id>
    <content type="text/html" src="/posts/artificial_potential_field_secant/" />
    <author>
      <name>freidank</name>
    </author>

  
    
    <category term="Robotics" />
    
  

  <summary>Artificial potential fields (APFs) offer an interesting approach to path planning. The use of “fake forces” makes it intuitive to combine the effects of different elements in the planning scene. However, a common a drawback is the creation of local minima, which prevent guaranteed convergence on the target.  Mathematics The topographic height or potential of a point is denoted \(\psi (\mathbf{z...</summary>

  </entry>

  
  <entry>
    <title>Particle Catching</title>
    <link href="/posts/particle_catching/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Particle Catching" />
    <published>2022-10-21T00:00:00-04:00</published>
  
    <updated>2025-01-12T21:56:30-05:00</updated>
  
    <id>/posts/particle_catching/</id>
    <content type="text/html" src="/posts/particle_catching/" />
    <author>
      <name>freidank</name>
    </author>

  
    
    <category term="Robotics" />
    
  

  <summary>The challenge involves tracking a target particle and planning a path which brings the player into contact with the target at a particular time.  Investigation  Trivial approach  The trivial solution is to simply command the particle to prosecute the target’s current position, without extrapolating its behavior into the future. We don’t consider this possibility further.  Naive approach  The ne...</summary>

  </entry>

</feed>


